Guide to the David Peck Todd Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings (including correspondence with publishers), (1873-1933); Series III; 5.75 linear feet (20 boxes)
  - Articles, published
    - "The Lick Observatory …," Science, 4 September 1885
      - notes, handwritten mss., clippings (Box 78, Folder 87)
    - "First Quinquennial Report of the Director of the Amherst College Observatory, 1881-1885," Viert. der Astron Gesel, 1886 (Box 78, Folder 88)
    - "The Prediction of Fine Seeing," The Side real Messenger, 2 copies, 1886 April (Box 78, Folder 89)
    - "On the Best Device for Revolving a Dome," Monthly Notices, R. A. S., 2 offprints, 1887 March (Box 78, Folder 90)
    - "On Observations of the Eclipse of 1887 Aug. 18, in Connection with the Electric Telegraph," American Journal of Science, March 1887 typed Mss., notes, offprint (Box 78, Folder 91)
    - "The Total Eclipse (August 1887) in Japan," The Observatory, cover page only (Box 78, Folder 92)
    - "Preliminary Report (Unofficial) on the Total Solar Eclipse of 1887," Amherst College Observatory
      - Offprint, 1888 (Box 78, Folder 93)
      - Another copy
        See: box 75
    - "Observations of Occultations during The Total Eclipse of the Moon, 1888, Jan. 28," Astronomical Journal, 23 March 1888 (Box 78, Folder 94)
    - "Doctor Hickok," The Independent, 24 May 1888 (Box 78, Folder 95)
    - "American Telescopes," Encyclopedia Brittannica, Appendix, American Reprint 1888, 2 copies (Box 78, Folder 96)
    - "Instructions for Observing the Total Eclipse of the Sun, Jan 1, 1889," Published by Amherst College Observatory, 1888 (Box 78, Folder 97)
      - Handwritten mss. and notes (Box 78, Folder 98)
    - "Note on Spurious Bows," American Meteorological Journal, 1888 December (Box 78, Folder 99)
    - "The New Year's Day Eclipse," Harper's Weekly correspondence, 29 December 1888 (Box 78, Folder 100)
      - Reprint (Box 78, Folder 101)
    - "Photographs of the Corona … Jan 1, 1889," Smithsonian Inst. (Box 78, Folder 102)
    - "Note on the Eclipse of Jan. 1, 1889," The Sidereal Messenger, 2 copies, 1889 February (Box 79, Folder 103)
    - "An American Eclipse Expedition in the Orient," Leslie's Popular Monthly, 1889 April (Box 79, Folder 104)
      - 2 copies, 1889 April (Box 79, Folder 105)
    - "Results of Observations on the Total Solar Eclipse of Jan. 1, 1889," Transactions, N. Y. Academy of Sciences, 1 April 1889 (Box 79, Folder 106)
      - Article only (Box 79, Folder 107)
    - "How Man's Messenger Outran the Moon," Century Illustrated Magazine, 1889 August (Box 79, Folder 108)
      - 2 copies (Box 79, Folder 109)
    - Letters to Brooklyn Standard Union, 1889 December (Box 79, Folder 110)
    - Letter from Northwest Coast of Africa Brooklyn Daily Standard Union, 19 December 1889 (Box 79, Folder 111)
    - Articles on Angola Expedition in NY Herald: "Sons of Science …," "The Eclipse,", 1889 December (Box 79, Folder 112)
    - Bulletins, nos. 1-18, U. S. Scientific expedition to W. Africa, No. 9 in Portuguese; D. P. Todd, ed., prepared no. 4, 9, 12, 17, 1889 1 November-31 December (Box 79, Folder 113)
    - "Total Solar Eclipse," Boston Herald: correspondence, 1890 January (Box 79, Folder 114)
    - "The U. S. Scientific Expedition to W. Africa, 1889," Nature, 1 May 1890 (Box 79, Folder 115)
    - "Telescopes Beneath the Southern Cross," Illustrated American, 28 June 1890 (Box 79, Folder 116)
    - "Modern Eclipse Problems," The Foru, 1890 July (Box 79, Folder 117)
    - "The South African Public Library, Cape Town," Papers and Proceedings of the 11th General Meeting of the American Library Association, 8-11 September 1890 (Box 79, Folder 118)
    - "The Automatic Operation of Photographic Apparatus:"
      - Early draft (Box 79, Folder 119)
      - Wilson's Photographic Magazine, 20 September 1890 (Box 79, Folder 120)
      - Scientific American Supplement, 2 copies, 4 October 1890 (Box 79, Folder 121)
    - "An Oddity in Eclipses," Harper's Weekly, 13 December 1890
      - Correspondence (Box 79, Folder 122)
      - Reprint:
        See: box 86a, scrapbook
    - "The Moon's Eclipse," Illustrated American, 12 December 1891 (Box 79, Folder 124)
    - Report of the National Academy of Sciences for the Year 1889, 2 papers by D. P. Todd are listed (text not available), publicity clipping, 1891 (Box 79, Folder 125)
    - "An Ascent of Fuji the Peerless," Century Illustrated Magazine, 1892 August
      - Correspondence (Box 79, Folder 126)
      - Magazine and clipping (Box 79, Folder 127)
    - "Data (Chiefly Meterological) Bearing upon the Selection of Stations for Observing the Total Eclipse of 1893, April 16," American Meteorological Journal, journal and offprint, 1893 January (Box 79, Folder 128)
    - "Automatic Eclipse Photography," The Photographic Times, 13 October 1893 (Box 79, Folder 129)
    - "Dimensions of Small Planets," Astronomy and Astrophysics, 1893 (Box 79, Folder 130)
    - "The Ancient Mexican Calendar," NY Independent, 22 November 1894 (Box 79, Folder 131)
    - "The Sun," Science, 12 July 1895 (Box 79, Folder 132)
    - "On Engineering Conditions Connected with the Mounting of Instruments Used on Eclipse Expeditions," Pcdgs, AAAS, 1897 (Box 79, Folder 133)
    - "Automatic Photography of the Corona," Astrophysical Journal, Journal, reprint, and handwritten mss., 1897 May (Box 79, Folder 134)
    - "Studying the Sun, Amherst Eclipse Expedition to Japan in 1896," The Outlook, 7 August 1897 (Box 79, Folder 135)
    - "The Eclipse of the Sun," The Outlook, 22 January 1898 (Box 79, Folder 136)
    - "The Geographic, Commercial and Scientific Profit," Statement in a symposium on the search for the North Pole, American Monthly, Review of Reviews, 1898 February (Box 79, Folder 137)
    - "On a Convenient Method of Adjusting a Polar Axis to the Diurnal Motion," Monthly Notices, Royal Astron. Soc., 1898 March (Box 79, Folder 138)
    - "notes on the Preparation of Reticles," Physical Review, 2 reprints, 1900 July (Box 79, Folder 139)
    - "On the Application of the Electric Telegraph to the Furtherance of Eclipse Research," etc. 3 short papers, Brit. A. A. S., Report of Meeting, page proofs, 1900 September (Box 79, Folder 140)
    - "On Laboratory Methods in Teaching Astronomy," Popular Astronomy, 2 copies, 1900 November (Box 79, Folder 141)
    - "On a Modified Form of Occultation …," Monthly Notices, R. A. S., Handwritten ms. and 1 copy, 1901 June (Box 79, Folder 142)
    - "What Eclipses of the Sun Teach Us," Popular Astronomy, 2 copies, 1901 Jun, July (Box 80, Folder 143)
    - "Amherst Eclipse Expedition to Singkep, 1901," Astrophysical Journal, Handwritten ms, printed copy, clipping, 1901 December (Box 80, Folder 144)
    - "The Singkep Mechanical Commutator," Journal of the British Astronomical Association, Handwritten ms. copied by Mabel L. Todd, printed copy, 21 February 1902 (Box 80, Folder 145)
    - "On a Hitherto Untried Form of Mounting …for a Telescope of Exceptional Size," American Journal of Science, correspondence, 1902 June (Box 80, Folder 146)
      See: box 24, folder 147
    - "On a Hitherto Untried Form of Mounting …for a Telescope of Exceptional Size," American Journal of Science, 2 copies, 1902 June (Box 80, Folder 147)
    - "Early History of Astronomy at Amherst College," Popular Astronomy, 1903 June (Box 80, Folder 148)
    - "Meaning of the Sunspots," New England Homestead, 2 copies, 31 October and 7 November 1903 (Box 80, Folder 149)
    - "The Solar Eclipse of 1905 in Spain," The Observatory, 1905 April (Box 80, Folder 150)
    - "Predictions for the Total Eclipse of the Sun, 30 Aug, 1905," Popular Astronomy Journal, Handwritten ms. and 2 printed copies, 1905 May (Box 80, Folder 151)
    - "How Eclipses are Predicted," Technical World Magazine, 1905 September
      - Correspondence (Box 80, Folder 152)
      - Handwritten ms., 1 copy (Box 80, Folder 153)
    - "Observations of 1905 Eclipse at Tripoli" (Box 80, Folder 154)
    - "Total Solar Eclipses in the 20th Century," Science, correspondence
    - "Local Predictions for the Total Solar Eclipse, of 1907, Jan 13-14 in Turkestan—Mongolia," American Journal of Sciences, March 1906
      - Reprint and clipping (Box 80, Folder 155)
      - Correspondence (Box 80, Folder 156)
    - Five papers read at 7th Annual Meeting of the Astronomical and Astrophysical Society of America, Dec 28-30, 1905, N. Y. of which 4 were printed in Science n.d. Vol. XXIII, no. 586; abstracts of 4 papers printed; 1 ms., 28 March 1906 (Box 80, Folder 157)
    - "The Lowell Expedition to Andes," Popular Astronomy, Vol XV, printed copy; clippings, 1907 November (Box 80, Folder 158)
    - "Observations of the Transit of Mercury, 1907, Nov 13," Astronomical Journal, printed article; notes, 23 January 1908 (Box 80, Folder 159)
    - "More Proof of Life on Mars," The Circle
      - Correspondence, 1908 February (Box 80, Folder 160)
      - Ms., 1908 February (Box 80, Folder 161)
    - "Story of the Mars Expedition"
      - Cosmopolitan, correspondence, 1908 March (Box 80, Folder 162)
      - Cosmopolitan, Vol XLIV, 3 copies; clippings, 1908 March (Box 80, Folder 163)
    - "The Highest Astronomical Observatory," Aeronautics, 2 copies, 1909 June (Box 80, Folder 164)
    - "Halley's Comet as seen from a Balloon," "On the Steadiness of a Balloon Basket," Astron. and Astroph. Soc. of America, 11th Meeting, printed abstract, 17-19 August 1910 (Box 80, Folder 165)
    - "Halley's Comet," American Book Company
      - Correspondence (Box 80, Folder 166)
      - from New Astronomy, 1910 (Box 80, Folder 167)
      - Pamphlets and photos (Box 80, Folder 168)
    - Printed matter, clippings about Halley's comet, 1910 (Box 80, Folder 169)
    - "An Open-Air Telescope," American Journal of Science, 2 copies, 1911 July (Box 80, Folder 170)
    - "A Plan for an Open-Air Telescope," Literary Digest, taken from Popular Astronomy (11 Oct 1911); newspaper clippings, 25 November 1911 (Box 80, Folder 171)
    - "The Science of Aeronautics Today," Country Life in America
      - Correspondence, 11 July 1911 (Box 80, Folder 172)
      - Reprint, 15 July 1911 (Box 81, Folder 173)
    - "The Spectroscope in Astronomy," Monthly Evening Sky News, 3 copies, December 1911 (Box 81, Folder 174)
    - Telegram, Astronomische Nachrichten, 12 January 1912 (Box 81, Folder 175)
    - "Optical Resolution of the Saturnian Ring," American Journal of Science
      - Correspondence, 1912 February (Box 81, Folder 176)
      - 2 copies, 1912 February (Box 81, Folder 177)
    - "Optical Resolution of the Ring of Saturn into its Component Satellites or Particles," Guide to Nature, 1912 April (Box 81, Folder 178)
    - "Three Centuries of Total Eclipses of the Sun in Mexico: 1850-2150"
      - in Popular Astronomy, 1913 June-July (Box 81, Folder 179)
      - Report of the 17th International Congress Of American States, ms. and reprint, 1912 (Box 81, Folder 180)
    - "Spectrum Analysis," Popular Mechanics
      - Correspondence, 1912 August (Box 81, Folder 181)
      - 1 copy, 1912 August (Box 81, Folder 182)
      - "El Análisis Espectra," Boletín de la Unión Panamericana, Spanish translation of "Spectrum Analysis," 1 copy, 1912 October (Box 81, Folder 183)
      - "A Analyse Espectral," Boletin da União Pan-Americana, Portuguese translation of "Spectrum Analysis,", 1913 February (Box 81, Folder 184)
      - "L' Analyse Spectrale," Bulletin de L'Union Pan Américaine, French translation of "Spectrum Analysis,", 1913 May (Box 81, Folder 185)
    - "The Total Eclipse of 1914," Popular Astronomy, 1 reprint, 1914 January (Box 81, Folder 186)
    - "The Total Eclipse of 1914 in Turkey and Persia," Nature, 12 May 1914 (Box 81, Folder 187)
    - "Amherst Eclipse Expedition"
      - Nature, 29 October 1914 (Box 81, Folder 188)
      - American Journal of Science, 2 copies, 1914 December (Box 81, Folder 189)
    - "Sir William Rowan Hamilton …"
      - Correspondence (Box 81, Folder 190)
      - In Atlantic Monthly, Handwritten and typed Mss., 1918 October (Box 81, Folder 191)
      - notes and photographs (Box 81, Folder 192)
    - "On Selecting Stations for the Totality of 1918, June 8, and Probable Cloud Conditions at Eclipse Time," Popular Astronomy, 1918 March (Box 81, Folder 193)
    - "The Conquest of the Arctic by Aircraft and Radio," Scientific Age, 1 copy, 1926 May (Box 81, Folder 194)
    - "A New Optical Projection Planetarium," Popular Astronomy
      - Correspondence (Box 81, Folder 195)
      - Multigraphed ms., annotated reprints, 1925 Aug, September (Box 81, Folder 196)
      - Research material (Box 81, Folder 197)
    - "Radio Check-ups of 1926 Eclipses," Scientific Age, 1925 May (Box 81, Folder 198)
    - "The Aero-Radio Astronomic Check-ups," Scientific Age, 1925 April (Box 81, Folder 199)
    - "What if People Do Ridicule You," American Magazine
      - Correspondence (Box 81, Folder 200)
      - 1 copy, 1920 October (Box 81, Folder 201)
    - "On the Accurate Adjustment of Stationary Corona Graphs…," Popular Astronomy, 1927 May (Box 81, Folder 202)
    - "On the Accurate Adjustment of Stationary Coronographs with Despatch," Popular Astronomy
      - Handwritten and typed ms., Galley proofs, 1927 May (Box 81, Folder 203)
      - 1 copy; 6 reprints (1 annotated), 1927 May (Box 81, Folder 204)
    - "Total Solar Eclipse, 1925 in N. Y., 1927 in Norway"
      - Correspondence, 1927 May (Box 81, Folder 205)
      - For Traval Bureau of Norwegian Railways, multigraph copy, 1927 May (Box 81, Folder 206)
    - "On Accurate and Speedy Adjustment of Coronagraphs …," Popular Astronomy
      - Correspondence (Box 81, Folder 207)
      - 2 reprints, 1932 August-September (Box 81, Folder 208)
    - "Automatic Photography of the Sun's Corona," Popular Astronomy
      - Correspondence, 1933 June-July (Box 81, Folder 209)
      - Handwritten ms., galley proofs, 1 printed copy, 1933 June-July (Box 81, Folder 210)
  - Articles for The Nation
    - David P. Todd bibliography (Box 82, Folder 211)
    - Correspondence, payments: (Box 82)
      - 1881-1889 inclusive (Box 82, Folder 212)
      - 1890-1899 (Box 82, Folder 213)
      - 1900-1915 (Box 82)
    - Reviews and notes:
      - 1880-1889 (Box 82, Folder 215)
      - 1890-1899 (Box 82, Folder 216)
      - 1901-1915 (Box 82, Folder 217)
  - Miscellaneous writings
    - Brief popular articles, reviews, letters to the editor: published
      - 1883-1890 (Box 83, Folder 218)
      - 1892-1901 (Box 83, Folder 219)
    - Work on Webster's Dictionary: correspondence; notes, lists, 1906-1908 (Box 83, Folder 220)
    - Brief popular articles, reviews, letters to the editor: published
      - 1907-1914 (Box 83, Folder 221)
      - 1917-28 August 1932 (Box 83, Folder 222)
      - Including 4 articles on 1932 Eclipse in Herald Tribune, 1932 July-September (Box 83, Folder 223)
  - Unpublished articles
    - Handy-book for the Astronomic Tyro, 1878 (Box 84, Folder 224)
    - "Department of Astronomy,", Circa1887 (Box 84, Folder 225)
    - "St. Helena in 1890"
      - Typed ms. portions; handwritten notes (Box 84, Folder 226)
      - Mss. and photos (Box 84, Folder 227)
    - "On the Prehistoric Corona,", 1894 (Box 84, Folder 228)
    - "The Shooting Stars of November," copy by Mabel Loomis Todd, 1892-1898 (Box 84, Folder 229)
    - Review; essays, fragments, 1900, 1912 (Box 84, Folder 230)
    - "On Modern Transportation: A Simple Mechanical Innovation…,", 1901 (Box 85, Folder 231)
    - "Recent Observations in the Philippines," 1 handwritten, 1 typed, Circa 1901 (Box 85, Folder 232)
    - "Visual Observations of Long-Period Variables"
      - No. 1, Circa 1915 (Box 85, Folder 233)
      - Research, no. 2 (Box 85, Folder 234)
    - Essays:
    - "Can Railways…" (Box 85, Folder 235)
    - "Origins of Aero Astronomy,", Circa 1919
    - Essays, notes, Circa 1922-1925 (Box 85, Folder 236)
    - "On the Projected Exhibit of Astronomy and Navigation …," handwritten mss; 2 typed copies, 1926 (Box 85, Folder 237)
    - "Earthquakes, Clouds and Eclipses …," handwritten mss.; 2 typed drafts, Circa 1926 (Box 86, Folder 238)
    - Essays, 1926-1928 (Box 86, Folder 239)
    - "Story of Astronomy," encyclopedia, unpublished correspondence, 1929-1930 (Box 86, Folder 240)
    - "When Chasing TransNeptunian Planets Was Work,", 3 April 1930 (Box 86, Folder 241)
    - "Naked Eye Venus,", 10 November 1932 (Box 86, Folder 241)
    - ix Popular Explanations of Astronomy, [post-1922] (Box 86, Folder 241)
      Why aren't there the same number of stars every night? How far does the earth move each day in its journey around the sun? Where do the stars go when the sun comes up? How many stars are visible from the southern hemisphere? How many stars are visible from the northern hemisphere? How do eclipses of the sun verify certain ancient dates?
    - "On an effective method of sealing an exposed dome against smoke, dust and fine snow,", undated (Box 86, Folder 241)
    - "The ? of Stars" (on Mars), undated (Box 86, Folder 241)
    - On Telescopes, undated (Box 86, Folder 241)
    - Fragments of two book reviews on astronomy, undated (Box 86, Folder 241)
    - Review of Sir Robert Ball, Popular Guide to the Heavens, handwritten draft, undated (Box 86, Folder 241)
    - "The First Astronomers,", [1924?] (Box 86, Folder 241)
    - Bibliography on Astronomy, handwritten list (Box 86, Folder 241)
    - Articles and notes related to eclipse of 1932 (Box 86, Folder 242)
    - Essays on aero-astronomy, 1932, undated (Box 86, Folder 243)
    - notes on musicians, [1880's?] (Box 86, Folder 244)
    - On death, [1896?] (Box 86, Folder 244)
    - Biographical sketch of Andrew Ellicott Douglass, handwritten (Box 86, Folder 244)
    - "The Passing of a Great Educator,", [ca. 1921] (Box 86, Folder 244)
    - "Sir William Rowan Hamilton, An Apostle of Pure Science," (2 versions), undated (Box 86, Folder 244)
    - "Evolution of Expositions,", 1926 (Box 86, Folder 244)
    - Misc. undated notes, not astronomical (Box 86, Folder 245-246)
    - Scrap notes, not astronomical (Box 86, Folder 247)
    - Unidentified material on publications (Box 86, Folder 248)
    - Scrapbook with clippings of published articles from 1888 to 1907 (Box 86A)
- Teaching and Lecturing, (1881-1927); Series IV; 1.75 linear feet (4 boxes)
  This series covers David Peck Todd's Amherst years and includes correspondence, photographs and memorabilia connected with the building of the Observatory and Observatory House. Todd also lectured extensively outside Amherst, and the correspondence, notes and publicity connected with these activities are arranged alphabetically by place.
  - Teaching: Amherst
    - Correspondence as Professor of Astronomy (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Astronomy, Reports to Pres., 1881-1887 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Summer school bulletins, 1883, 1891 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Navigation lectures notes, 1902 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Navigation lectures reference material (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Re: Dept. of Astronomy (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Student observations, enrollment lists (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Astronomy and navigation exams, 1905-1916 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Examples of student work: abstract, exam papers, 1895, 1907, 1911, 1914 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - "Aloha" Cruises: student reports, photographs, 1909, 1914 (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - Papers as Secretary of Faculty: Letters of Inquiry, Minutes of Faculty Meetings, Petitions from Students, etc., 1882-1908 (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - Fees for exams; correspondence re: practice of other institutions, 1886, 1892 (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - Faculty Senate reports over case of S. P. Clutia, 1893-1894 (Box 87, Folder 13)
    - Memorabilia (Box 88, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 88, Folder 14A)
  - Teaching
    - Colorado Summer School prospectus, etc. (Box 88, Folder 15)
    - Home Correspondence School, Springfield, Mass.: contract, prospectus, correspondence, 1902-1927 (Box 88, Folder 16)
    - International Correspondence School, Scranton, Pa.: Practical Astronomy Instruction Paper, 2 parts, 1906 (Box 88, Folder 17)
    - Smith:
      - Building of observatory, 1886 (Box 88, Folder 18)
      - Memorabilia, 1884-1886 (Box 88, Folder 19)
    - Univ. Extension Course for Conn. Valley, 1916-1917 (Box 88, Folder 20)
    - Course on Astronomy prospectus
    - Accounts of astronomy at Amherst (Box 88, Folder 21)
  - Observatory
    - Dedication of Lawrence Observatory, 1848 (Box 88, Folder 22)
    - Report on visits to European Observatories, April 1900 (Box 88, Folder 23)
    - Tentative address list by Mabel Loomis Todd for observatory circular (Box 88, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence on building, 1897-1906 (Box 89, Folder 25)
    - Survey of cost of American observatories, 1905 (Box 89, Folder 26)
    - Plans, drawings, written proposals (Box 89, Folder 27)
    - Sketches (Box 89, Folder 28)
    - Financial campaign, 1901-1906 (Box 89, Folder 29)
    - Cornerstone ceremony, June 23, 1903 (Box 89, Folder 30)
    - Journal of progress, 1903-1905 (Box 89, Folder 31)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1902, 1904 (Box 89, Folder 32)
    - Photographs of building of Observatory; of apparatus
      See: Todd-Bingham Picture Collection, MS 496E, Series I-IV
    - Memorabilia, printed (Box 89, Folder 33)
    - Guest book (Box 89, Folder 34)
    - Observatory House: trees, memorabilia of planting lists, correspondence, book (Box 89, Folder 35)
    - Lecture notes:
      - Re: Astronomy (Box 90, Folder 36)
      - Re: Pensacola trip, 1889 (Box 90, Folder 37)
    - Arizona (Box 90, Folder 38)
    - Connecticut:
      - Correspondence (B-H):
        - Bridgeport (Box 90, Folder 39)
        - Canaan (Box 90, Folder 39)
        - Enfield (Box 90, Folder 39)
        - Hartford (University) (Box 90, Folder 39)
        - Hartford (Technology Club) (Box 90, Folder 39)
      - Correspondence (N-S):
        - New Britain (Commonwealth Club) (Box 90, Folder 40)
        - New Haven: Yale, Sheffield Lecture Courses (Box 90, Folder 40)
        - Rockville Teachers Club (Box 90, Folder 40)
        - Stamford Science Society (Box 90, Folder 40)
  - Chittenden, Russell H. (New Haven)
    See: box 2, folder 68
  - Connecticut:
    - Clippings (Box 90, Folder 41)
    - Memorabilia (Box 90, Folder 42)
  - Florida:
    - Correspondence (Box 90, Folder 43)
    - Clippings (Box 90, Folder 44)
  - Maine: correspondence (Box 90, Folder 45)
  - Massachusetts:
    - Correspondence (A-G):
      - Amherst (Box 90, Folder 46)
      - Boston (Box 90, Folder 46)
      - Florence (Box 90, Folder 46)
      - Granby (Box 90, Folder 46)
    - Glidden, Etta. N. (Boston)
      See: box 4, folder 123
    - Correspondence (H-W):
      - Hatfield Men's Club (Box 90, Folder 47)
      - Haverhill (Box 90, Folder 47)
      - Holyoke Men's Club (Box 90, Folder 47)
      - Housatonic Lecture Club (Box 90, Folder 47)
      - Lenox Lecture Course (Box 90, Folder 47)
      - Methuen (Box 90, Folder 47)
      - Millington Centennial (Box 90, Folder 47)
      - New Bedford (Box 90, Folder 47)
      - New Salem (Box 90, Folder 47)
      - North Dana (Box 90, Folder 47)
      - Northampton (Telescopium) (Box 90, Folder 47)
      - Orange (Box 90, Folder 47)
      - Pittsfield (Box 90, Folder 47)
      - So. Hadley (Mt. Holyoke) (Box 90, Folder 47)
      - Springfield (Box 90, Folder 47)
      - Ware Men's League (Box 90, Folder 47)
      - Westfield (Box 90, Folder 47)
      - Worcester (Box 90, Folder 47)
    - Young, Anne S. (Mt. Holyoke)
      See: box 10, folder 361
    - Clippings (Box 90, Folder 48)
    - Amherst: clippings (Box 90, Folder 49)
    - Memorabilia (Box 90, Folder 50)
    - Amherst: memorabilia (Box 90, Folder 51)
  - New Jersey:
    - Correspondence (Box 90, Folder 52)
    - Clippings (Box 90, Folder 53)
  - New York
    - Correspondence (1):
      - Binghamton (Box 90, Folder 54)